# ANDRÉ SCHOLL

A. Moser Street 352503 Biel/Bienne☑ andre.scholl@hispeed.ch

+41 78 638 37 19

August 11th, 1991 Swiss





# PhD Candidate in Information Systems, Master of Arts in Economics

My main purpose and source of motivation are to use the most relevant methodological, conceptual, and team collaboration methods to reach innovative research results and insights.

- Analytically skilled
- Organized

Conscientious

Perceptive

Versatile

Gifted in learning

### **DEMONSTRATED CORE COMPETENCIES**

## **Project Implementation and Management**

- o Plan and independently realize the project steps and processes for my PhD research articles
- o Organized, as group leader, the processes, guidance, and ongoing support of a data collection team
- o Planned and executed the programming of complete software on several projects autonomously

# **Data Processing and Analysis**

- o Combined different raw data sources and fully and autonomously created statistical economic indicators
- o Orchestrated scientific regressions, tests, and econometric analyses
- o Realized data plausibilization, consolidation, and correction in different fields

## **Achievement of Excellent Results with Advanced Techniques**

- o Developed further my R language data processing tools to import different types of data, draw conclusions from them through complex calculations, and summarize the results in Excel
- o Trained completely in SAS language (including integrated SQL) to merge various data and create indicators
- o Deepened further my object-oriented programming with VBA and examined links between Microsoft Office software to develop a data creation and management program
- o Increased my knowledge of Stata for the processing of data treatment, econometric tests, and regressions

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Research Assistant and PhD Candidate | University of Berne

03.2020 -

Achieve teaching and administrative tasks in Information Systems and conduct research on Open Data (OD), Open Government Data (OGD), and Linked Data (LD); German and English

Scientific Collaborator | University of Neuchâtel

12.2019 - 02.2020

Realized scientific analysis on a freelance and time-limited project in Economics and Energy; English and French (was hired mid-December 2019 unofficially and in February 2020 officially)

Trademark Examiner | Swiss Federal Institute of Intellectual Property, Bern

08.2019 - 10.2019

Examined thoroughly various trademarks to determine their degree of adequacy with current legislation and practice; German and French

Consultant | Polynomics AG, Olten

05.2019 - 06.2019

Achieved a time-limited scientific mandate in the IT and bandwidth Internet areas, and principally treated and analysed different data sources; German and English

University Intern | Swiss Federal Statistical Office, POKU Section, Neuchâtel

11.2018 - 04.2019

Implemented a new project assessing the cultural economy in Switzerland; French and German

Research Assistant | Berner Fachhochschule BFH, Bern and Fribourg

03.2018 - 04.2019

Developed independently and was responsible for programming, technical, and process flow aspects for a research project on the Swiss apprenticeship market; English and German

Assistant at Master level | Chair of Industrial Economics, University of Fribourg

10-12.2017

Supported the Chair for research and teaching tasks; during a limited period, due to budget reasons; Ger and Eng

Administrative Employee (teleworking); French | Instants Zen Sàrl, Formangueires (FR)

09.2016 - 05.2018

Civil Servant; French, German, and English

09-10.2010 / 01-08.2011 / 09.2015 - 03.2016

Institute of Federalism | Cantonal and University Library, Fribourg | Special Education Library | Fribourg Cantonal Hospital | Jura Cantonal Library, Porrentruy

#### **EDUCATION**

PhD in Information Systems   University of Bern	03.2020 -
Certificate of Advanced Studies in Teaching in Higher Education   University of Bern	09.2021 -
Doctoral Program   Several universities	2020 - 2022
Master of Arts in Economics   University of Fribourg	04.2019

Specializations: Public Sector Economics and Public Policy, Industrial Economics, Econometrics

Master's Thesis: Lorsque les signaux de prix se font subtils, ou les effets sur l'immobilier d'un système de péréquation financière / When price signals become subtle, or the effects on real estate of a fiscal equalization system; 5/6

Magna cum laude Distinction; Overall Rating: 5.43/6

> Trilingual Teaching and Distinction: English, German, and French

Complement in Philosophy (QUALI+) | University of Fribourg 2017 - 2018 **Bachelor of Science in Economics** | University of Neuchâtel 2015

Majors: Economics, Finance

Cum Laude Distinction; Overall Rating: 5.43/6

**Bilingual Maturity German French** | Seeland Gymnasium Biel 2010

Majors: Computer Science, Biology, and Chemistry; Overall Rating: 5.42/6

#### **AWARDS**

Guido Pult   Best student in the Bachelor of Science in Economics, Major in Economics	2015
Société Neuchâteloise des Sciences Economiques   Best average grade of the Bachelor of Science in Economics	2015
Peter Dolder, Foundation for Democracy, Bern   Award for excellency in Maturity Thesis	2010

### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Association Forum Partnersprachen Freiburg/Forum Langue Partenaire Fribourg: Organize events	Since 2017
Swiss Association for Intellectually Gitfted Teenagers and Adults ASAAS: Organized events	2021 - 2022
National Youth Council of Switzerland: Supported young people for political commitments	2016, 2017 & 2019

## **LANGUAGES**

French Native Language

English Excellent Knowledge C1-C2, Academic English II C1+ 2017, Certificate in Advanced

**English C1** 2015

German Excellent Knowledge C1-C2, Goethe-Zertifikat C1 2018, Deutsch als Fremdsprache C1 2017,

Language Study vacation C1 II and WWOOFing 2016

Swiss German Ability to use in daily life Italian Elementary proficiency

## **INFORMATICS**

- Statistical processing and coding: professional use of R, Stata, SAS, and MAXQDA
- Universal programming: extended knowledge in VBA and Python
- Web development and layout: some skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Markdown, LaTeX, XML
- \* Relational database systems: good knowledge of MySQL and SQL
- Knowledge and great personal interest in data science and machine learning

Interests: Board games, poetry, literatures, Krav Maga, table tennis, outdoor sports, violin